有史以来第一次，
For the first time in history,
黄金阵营！
the Gold Faction!
驾！
Hyah!
两千塞斯特斯换我女儿奥拉的自由
Two thousand sesterces for
my daughter Aura's freedom.
上帝保佑
By the Gods.
罗马的皇帝必须站着死去才能成为神。
An Emperor of Rome must
die standing to become divine.
死了多少人
How many dead?
约200 μ战斗仍在郊区继续。
About 200. Fighting still
continues in the Suburra.
我父亲的葬礼？
My father's funeral?
明天可以继续了。
Safe to go ahead tomorrow.
参议员们
Senators.
我认为这些游戏的目的
I thought the intention
of these games
是为了安抚民众而不是激怒他们
was to calm the
citizens, not inflame them.
问题是这个新的黄金派系。
The problem is this
new Gold Faction.
只有我们四个的时候一切都很稳定。
Things were stable when
we were just the four of us.
当一个新的派系
What do you expect
when a new faction
是一个平民和该死的叙利亚人的
is owned by a plebeian
and a damned Syrian.
它给了较低层次的想法。
It gives the lower orders ideas.
你有什么建议
So, what do you counsel?
很简单，结束黄金阵营。
Simple, end the Gold Faction.
有趣.
Interesting.
先把这个放一边。
Let's put that aside
for one moment.
我有个更大的问题希望你能给点建议。
I have a greater concern about
which I would welcome your input.
这是从国王时代开始的
This is since the
time of the kings
只有三个罗马人，朱利叶斯·凯撒，凯撒·奥古斯都和克劳迪亚斯
only three Romans, Julius Caesar,
Caesar Augustus and Claudius have been
被神化，被宣布为神。
deified, declared Gods.
我的父亲维斯帕先大帝也应该被神化
My father, the Great Emperor
Vespasian, should, too, be deified,
并以神的身份加入他们
and join them as a God.
這是一個大膽的要求。
That's a bold request.
牧師和螺旋鑽告訴我們他已經贏得了他應有的地位
The priests and augers tell us
that he has earned his rightful place
在不朽者中。
among the Immortals.
就像你的四個派系
Just as your four
factions have earned you
馬克西姆斯馬戲團的獨家經營權
the exclusive right to
run at Circus Maximus.
我向神父們鞠躬。
I bow to the priests.
我們會在參議院
And we'll move in the Senate
將維斯帕先皇帝奉為神明
to deify the Emperor Vespasian.
我也會。
As will I.
看起來怎麼樣？
How does it look?
- 黃金！- 一面旗幟！
- Gold!
- A flag!
打倒那些人！
Down with those!
奉提圖斯·凱撒·維斯帕西亞努斯皇帝之命
By order of Emperor
Titus Caesar Vespasianus,
允許在馬克西姆斯馬戲團跑步
permission to run
in Circus Maximus
特此退出黃金陣營
is hereby withdrawn
from the Gold Faction.
走吧
Let's go.
方索阿等等
Fonsoa, wait!
- 冷靜點- 冷靜？
- Calm down.
- Calm down?
我不幹了。
I quit the Blue.
我告訴馬蘇斯和安東尼婭去死吧。
I told Marsus and Antonia
to go fuck themselves.
他們干自己總比你干她好。
Better they fuck
themselves than you fuck her.
不，不別開玩笑。
No, no, don't make jokes.
我是被你操的人。
I am the one being
fucked by you.
阿塔加提斯，我為什麼要聽這個羅馬傻瓜的話？
Atargatis, why did I
listen to this Roman fool?
天蠍座是羅馬最好的車手，有史以來最好的，
Scorpus is the best
driver in Rome, best ever,
史上最高薪酬
highest paid in history.
我就为了这场“黄金秀”放弃了这一切？
And I threw it all away
for this "golden shitshow"?
天蝎座，冷静点。
Scorpus, settle yourself.
你的伟大毋庸置疑。
Your greatness
goes unquestioned.
我能解决的
I can fix this.
我想这些是我的战车。
I believe these are my chariots.
加夫罗斯？
Gavros?
啊，白色！
Ah, White!
立刻带他们出去。
Take them out immediately.
等等不，不！
Wait. No, no!
埃利亚安静！和平！
Elia! Peace! Peace!
你们只不过是普通的小偷！
You're nothing more
than common thieves!
- 我花钱买的。- 我也是
- I paid for those.
- So did I.
其实我没付钱
Well, I didn't
actually pay for them.
但我一直在考虑。
But I was thinking about it.
我受够了
I'm done.
天蝎座不再有黄金阵营。
No more Gold
Faction for Scorpus.
我不玩了
I'm out.
出去！
Out!
凭借诸神的恩典和力量，
By the grace and
power of the Gods,
我们加冕提图斯·弗拉维乌斯·维斯帕西亚努斯
we crown Titus
Flavius Vespasianus,
罗马的领袖和皇帝。
Leader and Emperor of Rome.
那些女人是谁
Who are those women?
维斯塔尔家族，
The Vestal Virgins,
罗马永恒火焰的守护者
guardians of
Rome's eternal flame,
没有接触过，未婚，只为城市所爱
untouched, unmarried,
loved only by the city itself.
他们有强大的力量。
They have great powers.
他们中的一个人只要看一眼就能救一个被判死刑的人。
A mere look from one of them
can save a condemned man.
一触即解放奴隶。
A touch can set a slave free.
我是她的证人。
That one, I was her witness.
她是我情妇安东尼娅的女儿。
She's the daughter of
my mistress Antonia.
她只有七岁
She was only seven
她就死了
when the Vestals took her.
她哭着恳求父母不要把她送走。
She cried, begging her
parents not to give her away.
一个母亲怎么能这么做？
How could a mother do that?
神父，我不想冒犯你。但你疯了吗？
Father, I don't wish to
offend you. But are you mad?
对尿液征税？
A tax on urine?
这不是对尿液征税，
It's not a tax on urine,
这是对尿液的销售征税。
it is a tax on
the sale of urine.
尿液呈白色，
Urine bleaches white,
我们穿的衣服你明白吗？
the clothes that we
wear. Do you understand?
钱，闻闻。
Money, smell it.
算了吧。
Smell it.
你觉得这味道难闻吗？
Do you find that
smell offensive?
- 它没有气味。- 没错
- It has no smell.
- Precisely.
钱，它支付我们的军团。
Money, it pays for our legions.
它帮助我们为公民提供健康的沐浴，
It helps us supply our citizens
with baths for their health,
这样他们就不会起来割破我们的喉咙
so that they don't rise
up and slit our throats.
钱
Money.
一个皇帝，即使是未来的皇帝，
An emperor, even
a prospective one,
知道钱不臭。
knows that money does not stink.
它可以建立你的遗产。
It can build your legacy.
兄弟兄弟
Brother. Brother.
罗马人，
Romans,
我，泰特斯·弗拉维乌斯·韦斯帕西安，
I, Titus Flavius Vespasian,
站在你面前，一个皇帝，
stand before you, an emperor,
将军，
general,
还有一个悲伤的儿子
and a grieving son.
我父亲把弗拉维安圆形剧场给了你
My father gave you
the Flavian Amphitheater
举办世界上最伟大的运动会
to hold the greatest
games on Earth.
我的遗产，
My legacy,
我将重建现在已成废墟的处女座水道。
I shall reconstruct the
Aqueduct Virgo now in ruin.
水会为每个罗马人的利益而流动。
Water will flow for the
benefit of every Roman.
再一次，我会给你最好的公共浴池
And once more, I will give
you the greatest public baths
人类所见过的。
ever seen by man.
把所有东西都搬进去。
Move everything in.
是的，我的女王。
Yes, my queen.
是的，把那个和这个拿来，女士们。
Yes, bring that one
and this one, women.
是的，先吃这个，继续。
Yes, this one first, go
on, go ahead, go ahead.
- 我能和你说句话吗，亲爱的？- 能等等吗
- May I have a word, my love?
- Can it wait?
告诉我，谁来为你建造这些浴场重塑罗马？
Tell me, who is going to build these
baths and remake Rome for you?
我们以后再谈这个。
We'll talk about that later.
你答应过我你成为皇帝后会释放我的人民
You promised you would free my
people after you became Emperor,
但我现在明白你并不想这么做
but I see now you had
no intention of doing so.
你寻求这样的承诺，我从来没有给过。
You sought such a
promise, I never gave it.
没说得这么清楚
Not in so many words.
我的话很准确。
My words were precise.
我告诉过你我会做的
I told you I would do it
如果这是为了罗马的利益
if it was in the
interest of Rome.
但我看到的不是这样。
A vision has told me otherwise.
幻象？
A vision?
是的，我父亲在至福乐土和我说话，
Yes, my father spoke to
me from the Elysian Fields,
让我为罗马的荣耀建造这些浴场
told me to build these
baths for the glory of Rome.
因此，我很高兴能利用你的人。
As such, it pleases me to
use your people to that end.
你骗了我
You lied to me.
如你所说后
As you said. Later.
骚乱已被平息。
The rioting has been quelled.
但现在人们担心粮仓会再次空无一物，
But there is now fear that the
granaries will be empty again,
粮食是故意延迟的
that the grain was
delayed intentionally.
有传言说食物短缺的幕后黑手是弗拉维安人。
And rumors that a Flavian
was behind the food shortages.
个...弗拉维安？
A... A Flavian?
那不可能是父亲，当然也不是我
That's impossible that it was
Father, and certainly not me,
那就剩下...
and that leaves...
你有所隐瞒。
You're holding something back.
你有两个缺点。
You have two faults.
什么，只有两个？
What, only two?
两个重要的。
Two that matter.
你爱你的女主人爱得太深了，
You love your mistress
more than you should,
你对你哥哥的信任超过了你应该信任的程度
and you trust your brother
more than you ought.
第一个错误，嗯...
The first fault, um...
那是我的事。
that is my affair.
至于我哥哥，好吧，我爱他，真的，但我不是傻瓜。
As for my brother, well, I
love him, true, but I am no fool.
你认为他是粮食延误和暴乱的幕后黑手？
You think him behind the
grain delays, behind the riots?
有传言说。
There are rumors.
看看是否有实质内容。
Find out if there's
substance to them.
我们有麻烦了
We have a problem.
下一个，来吧。200赌瑞德。
Next, come on.
Two hundred on Red.
我们至少有20个。
We got 20 at least.
Saranta Leuko.
- Sorenkto！- 萨兰塔
- Sorenkto!
- Saranta?
萨兰塔·利科？
Saranta Leuko?
四十押白色。
Forty on white.
走！喊出你的赌注。我说了让开！
Move! Shout your
bets. I said move!
动
Move.
喊出你的赌注！
Shout out your bets!
我说了让开。
I said move.
给我50
Give me 50.
100赌蓝色
One hundred on blue.
50赌蓝色
Fifty on blue.
殿下
Your Highness.
是其他老板说服我哥哥除掉黄金派的。
It was the other owners that convinced
my brother to get rid of the Gold Faction.
我也这么想。你能让我们复职吗？
I thought as much. Can
you get us reinstated?
也许吧
Perhaps.
我需要你先做件事。
There is something
I need you to do first.
你的前任，我的幕后黑手。
Your predecessor,
my doer of dark deeds.
- 一个叫卢修斯的- 我很不幸遇见了他。
- A certain Lucius.
- I've had the misfortune of meeting him.
他并不像我们希望的那样深藏在暗处。
He was not as deep in the
shadows as we might have hoped.
我要你掩盖他的踪迹。
I need you to
obscure his tracks.
他们把粮食短缺和粮食骚乱归咎于你。
They blame you for the grain
shortages and the food riots.
还没有，但怀疑离指责也不远了.
Not yet, but suspicion is
a short step from blame.
我来处理。这是我的荣幸。
I'll take care of it.
It'll be my pleasure.
尽你所能让我们的黄金阵营再次恢复。
And do what you can to get
our Gold Faction reinstated again.
这听起来更像是一个命令。
That sounded rather
like a command.
你是我的客户不是我的搭档
You're my client,
not my partner.
你为我的利益服务，希望我屈尊为你服务。
You serve my interests in
the hope I deign to serve yours.
原谅我。我会照你说的做。
Forgive me. I'll
do what you ask.
和图密善在一起的那个人是谁
Who was that man with Domitian?
他叫Tenax
His name is Tenax.
他来自郊区。还是个罪犯
He's from the
Suburra. And a criminal.
我需要更多地了解他。
I need to know more about him.
快来救我！快来救我！
Come for me! Come for me!
还有其他人吗卢修斯
Is there anyone else, Lucius?
号我什么都告诉你了我发誓
No. I told you
everything. I swear.
来吧，
Come on,
不会崩溃
isn't going to break.
再用力点。
Give it to him harder.
一些非常令人担忧的事情。
Something that
is of great concern.
兄弟，我希望你能和猶太女王一起忙碌
Brother, I expect you to be
busy with the Queen of Jews
晚上的這個時候。
this time of night.
小心點你走的冰沒有那麼厚。
Careful now. The ice
you walk on is not so thick.
有一個人，據說是最近糧食暴動的領導者，盧修斯。
There's a man, said to have
led the recent food riots, Lucius.
- 你知道他嗎？- 號
- Do you know of him?
- No.
嗯，有人說他是你的雇員。
Well, some say
he's of your employ.
有人說提圖斯養猴子和狗。
Some say Titus beds
monkeys and dogs.
這是真的嗎
Does that make it true?
我不認識他，陛下。
I do not know him, My Emperor.
那你就不會在乎盧修斯的死了
Then you will not care
that this Lucius is dead.
先被打，
Beaten first,
也許是為了獲取信息
perhaps for information.
或許是為了消遣。
Perhaps for pleasure.
和盧修斯在一起的人也死了
Men seen with
Lucius are dead also.
奧斯蒂亞的港務長
The Harbor Master at Ostia,
都是運糧的。
all were involved
in grain delivery.
就像他們在掩蓋自己的蹤跡。
As if they were
covering their tracks.
兄弟看著我的眼睛
Brother, look me in the eye.
你是不是為了讓我難堪而推遲了糧食的運送？
Did you delay the grain
delivery to embarrass me?
你覺得我會讓父親難堪嗎
You think I would
embarrass Father?
我讓黑幫找弗拉維安人的血，只是為了讓你難堪？
That I'd have the mob call for Flavian
blood, simply to embarrass you?
- 是嗎？- 號
- Did you?
- No.
我弟弟被關在他的房間裡。
My brother is to be
confined to his chambers.
- 沒有我的允許，他不會離開的。- 但是哥哥...
- He will not leave without my permission.
- But brother...
在我找到事情的真相之前，他會一直待在這裡。
And he shall remain, until I've
found the truth of the matter.
離開我
Leave me.
你相信他嗎？
Do you believe him?
我還不能決定
I can't yet decide.
暴亂對他來說也是一個風險。
The riot would have
been a risk for him also.
還有艦隊的船長，但他們在海上。
There are still the fleet
captains, but they are at sea.
一旦他們登陸，把他們帶到我面前。
Once they make landfall,
bring them before me.
- 你沒事吧？- 勉強
- Are you all right?
- Barely.
我差點就死了。
I just came close to death.
你認為貝雷妮絲是在給他建議嗎？
Do you think Berenice
is advising him?
當然了她知道我對她和她的人民的憤怒。
Of course. She knows my
ire towards her and her people.
殺了多少人，羅馬的五千個兒子？
Killers of how many, five
thousand sons of Rome?
為什麼不讓Tenax照顧她？
Why not have
Tenax attend to her?
煽動我哥哥對情人的報復？
And incite a lover's
vengeance in my brother?
並不是所有的猶太人
Not all the Judeans
are comfortable
讓他們的女王為你弟弟張開雙腿
with the idea of their queen
spreading her legs for your brother.
你怎麼知道的
And how would you know that?
我在工地有眼線。
I have ears at the
construction site.
有傳言說他們在秘密會面，
There are rumors
of meetings in secret,
斯巴達人起義的可能性正在討論中
where the possibility of a
Spartacan revolt is being discussed...
他們的一個長輩，
One of their elders,
據說建築師亞撒利雅稱她為提圖斯的妓女。
the architect, Azariah, has been
heard to call her Titus's whore.
幹得好
Well done.
你看，
See,
我可不只是個混蛋和一張嘴。
I am more than an
ass and a mouth.
我們要離間他們，
We'll drive a wedge
between them,
我哥哥
my brother
和他的妓女
and his whore.
出去！
Out!
我要和我女兒談談，
I need to speak
with my daughter,
求你了
please.
母親
Mother.
- 我不能久留。- 我知道我知道
- I cannot stay long.
- I know, I know.
你對他們的女兒了解多少？女祭司？
What do you know about
their daughter? The priestess?
我從沒聽說過有女兒。
I have never heard
about a daughter.
他們有個兒子。
They have a son.
他們經常談論他。
They often speak about him.
朱利葉斯為什麼？為什麼？
Julius. Why?
德魯斯利亞呢
And Drusilla?
你注意到她外出有什麼規律嗎？
Have you noticed any
routines in her outings?
有一次，她在日落的時候帶著一些微不足道的東西出去了。
One time, she went out at
sundown with some paltry goods.
好.看著她，告訴我.
Good. Watch her and let me know.
嗯？
Hmm?
茱拉
Jula!
走了走了
Go now. Go.
御車者天蠍座執政官
The charioteer, Scorpus, Consul.
天蠍座！
Ah, Scorpus!
什麼風把您吹來了？
To what do I owe
the honor of this visit?
我覺得我們的合作關係太重要了不能結束。
I've decided that our
partnership is too valuable to end.
天蠍座願意出個好價錢，
Scorpus is willing,
for the right price,
是的，凱旋迴到藍派。
yes, to return triumphantly
to the Blue Faction.
你真是太慷慨了，天蠍座。
That's very generous
of you, Scorpus.
但是氙氣呢？我們僱用了他來代替你。
But what of Xenon? We've
hired him in your stead.
氙氣是，呃......你知道，他是個好司機，我承認，
Xenon is, uh... You know,
he's a good driver, I admit,
但他不是天蠍座。
but he is no Scorpus.
他比天蝎座更忠诚。
He's more loyal than Scorpus.
也许我欠你一个道歉。
Perhaps I owe you an apology.
为？
For?
- 呃，为了...... - 他妈的老婆？
- Uh, for...
- Fucking his wife?
一句话，是的。
In a word, yes.
我可以为我们两个人说话吗，我的爱人？
May I speak for the
two of us, my love?
当然，我们是一体的。
Of course, we speak as one.
总是。
Always.
我们支付给 Xenon 的费用是我们付给您的三倍。
We're paying Xenon three
times what we paid you.
即使你出现，我们也不会雇用你
We wouldn't hire you
back even if you showed up
嘴里满是珍珠和印度红宝石
with your mouth full of
pearls and an Indian ruby
从你屁股上掉下来的鸡蛋的大小。
the size of a hen's egg
falling out of your ass.
去他妈的吧。
Go fuck yourselves.
该死的罗马人。
Fucking Romans.
我很乐意操我的丈夫。
I'd happily fuck my husband.
任何人，只要不是你。
Anyone, as long as it's not you.
就这样。
Right this way.
你继续让我惊叹。
You continue to amaze me.
謝謝。
Thank you.
呸。
Ugh.
我警告过你父亲，禁止你嫁给那个男人。
I warned your father to forbid
you from marrying that man.
Caltonia.
我好慚愧
I'm so ashamed.
你家人知道嗎？
Does your family know?
自從我母親去世後，我的叔叔們就拋棄了我們。
Since my mother's death,
my uncles have abandoned us.
父親開始喝酒了
Father's turned to wine,
我們的莊園也消失了。
and our estates are gone.
我只有藍派的股份
All I had were those
shares in the Blue Faction.
我和我的擁護者談過了。
I've spoken to my advocates.
那些股份被你丈夫偷走了
Those shares were
stolen by your husband.
你要離開這裡，
You will leave this place,
住在我家
live under my roof,
我們將一起進入法庭，奪回屬於你的東西。
and together, we will enter the
courts and get back what is yours.
你願意為我這麼做？
You would do that for me?
我愛你孩子
I love you, child.
我們會把他們找回來的。
We will get them back.
我會出高價從你手裡買下他們
And I will buy them from
you at an exorbitant price.
然後你和我我們會慶祝我們的...
And then you and I,
we will celebrate our...
我們的合作關係。
Our partnership.
早上好，蘭圖勒斯。
Morning, Lentullus.
周末前我需要兩輛戰車
I need two chariots
by the week's end.
- 不，這不可能。- 沒有什麼是不可能的
- No, that's impossible.
- Nothing's impossible.
- 這些呢？- 哦
- What about these?
- Oh.
一年前，
Well, a year ago,
我用最輕的木頭做實驗，
I experimented with
the lightest of woods,
並剃掉支柱，讓它們和我的手指一樣薄。
and shaved the struts, made
them as thin as my finger.
他們很快，很快，
They were fast, so fast,
但太輕了無法通過重量限制
but too light to get past
the weight restrictions.
他們能在周末前準備好嗎？
Can they be ready by
the end of the week?
是的，但你永遠無法讓他們通過檢查。
Yes, but you'll never
get them past inspection.
那是我的問題
Let that be my problem.
哦，還有，呃，金色的油漆，
Oh, and the, uh, golden paint,
減少它的光澤。更有品位。
give it less shine.
More tasteful.
感謝大家的到來。
Thank you all for coming.
我們一起做，就像你們羅馬人一樣。
We do this all together,
just like you Romans.
- 是嗎-是的效率更高。
Yes? Much more efficient.
是啊，大家都知道你能為我們開車是我們的福氣。
Yes, well, it's no secret that we'd all
be fortunate to have you driving for us.
你很貴也不是什麼秘密。
And it's no secret
that you're expensive.
這是自然
That goes without saying.
是的，好吧，失去了氙，顯然，我感興趣。
Yes, well, having lost
Xenon, clearly, I'm interested.
- 你需要什麽？- 簡單.
- What do you need?
- Simple.
如果天蠍座想在馬戲團昂首挺胸
If Scorpus is to hold his
head high in the Circus,
他的報酬肯定比氙高
he must be paid more than Xenon.
一百零八？不，對我來說太富有了。
A million eight? No,
too rich for my blood.
我不玩了
I'm out.
祝你們好運
Good luck to you all.
來吧孩子們
Come, boys.
我也退出。
And I'm out, too.
不，不，等等。號
No, no, wait. No.
你不能把我留給一個投標人。
You can't leave
me with one bidder.
- 我可以為你贏。- 我不想贏。
- I can win for you.
- I don't want to win.
- 你當然知道- 我贏不起。
- Of course you do.
- I can't afford to win.
我靠聰明賺錢。
I profit by being smart.
我降低了成本，讓我的競爭對手
I cut my costs down
and let my competitors
用金子感謝我幫他們贏了
thank me with gold
for helping them win.
祝你好運
Good luck.
所以，我們在這裡。
So, here we are.
一百零八。
A million eight.
不，109萬，因為氙是支付108萬。
No, a million nine, because
Xenon is being paid a million eight.
嗯.我沒看到其他人出價。
Hmm. I don't see
anyone else bidding here.
它會增加你的尊嚴...
It will add to your dignitas...
給我的錢比瑪蘇斯給氙的多
to pay me more than
Marsus is paying Xenon.
是的我有足夠的尊嚴。
Yes. Well, I have
sufficient dignitas.
謝謝你天蠍座
Thank you, Scorpus.
六十萬。
Six hundred thousand.
這樣的開場白傷害了我的感情。
Such an opening
offer hurts my feelings.
這不是開場白
Not an opening offer.
這是我最後一次了
It's my final one.
我是天蠍座。
I am Scorpus.
是的，我付錢。
Yes, and I'm paying.
聽著，如果能安撫你的情緒，我們可以，呃，
Look, if it will soothe your
feelings, we can always, uh,
告訴全世界是一百零九
tell the world it
was a million nine.
好孩子
Good boy.
天蠍座？
Scorpus?
現在不行
Not now.
但你想慶祝。
But you wanted to celebrate.
嗯，確保他得到一些關注。
Hmm, make sure that
he gets some attention.
他剛和白人簽約了。
He just signed with the Whites.
哦親愛的
Oh, dear.
我記得它更大。
I remember it being bigger.
更堅定。
And firmer.
我們都變老了，我想。沒辦法
We all get older, I
suppose. No way around it.
誰讓你進來的
Who let you in?
我見到了市政官盧迪。
I met with the Aedile Ludi.
好消息他很快就會恢復我們的黃金陣營。
Good news. He'll soon be
reinstating our Gold Faction.
訂購了新的裝備，是馬戲團有史以來最輕的。
New rigs ordered, the lightest
the Circus has ever seen.
你會像風一樣飛起來的，我的朋友。
You'll be flying like
the wind, my friend.
很快不是現在。
Soon is not now.
我剛簽了懷特一家的合同。
I have just signed
for the Whites.
你這個忘恩負義的小混蛋。
You ungrateful little bastard.
我把你從你媽的皮條客手裡救了出來。
I pulled you from the
clutches of your mother's pimp.
為此，我感謝你。
For that, I thank you.
你，前三場勝利都來自我的修復。
You, whose first three
wins were all from my fixes.
是的，是的，是的。你做了很多，但我也是。
Yes, yes, yes, yes.
You did a lot, but so did I.
你是對的
You're right.
我的脾氣控制了我。
My temper overtook me.
或許我們應該各走各的路。
Perhaps we should
go our separate ways.
睡一覺吧
Get some sleep.
當你和我的西班牙人比賽的時候你會需要它的。
You'll need it when you
drive against my Spaniards.
它們讓我想起了你，
They remind me of you,
你知道，當你在你的黃金時期。
you know, when you
were in your prime.
尤其是那個安德里亞。
Especially that Andria.
是啊，我看到有一天你的身體
Yeah, I see a day when your body
正在馬戲團的脊柱里腐爛
is rotting in the
spina of the Circus,
他讓整個羅馬都忘了你的存在
and he's making all of
Rome forget you ever existed.
祝你和白人好運
Good luck with the Whites.
然後我們會帶來50個布里甘廷侏儒。
And then we are bringing
in 50 Brigantine midgets.
讓他們和同樣數量的鬥牛犬競爭。
And pit them against an
equal number of bull-hounds.
我是說，還有什麼更好的方式來榮譽提圖斯·弗拉維烏斯的崛起嗎？
I mean, is there any finer way
to honor Titus Flavius' ascent?
矮人與狗，
Dwarfs versus dogs,
你就這點能耐嗎
is that the best you can do?
號我是說，你有沒有...你看到那些狗了嗎？
No. I mean, have you...
Have you seen the dogs?
來吧來吧你還有什麼？
Come, come. What
else do you have?
哦
Oh.
盧杜斯·比斯特烏斯收到了一批有趣的紅屁股猴子
Ludus Beastius has received an
interesting number of red-assed monkeys,
它們都是雄性，我們可以建造一個外殼，
and they're all males, and
we could build an encasement,
一片森林在野外，柵欄不太高。
a forest in the wild,
fence not too high.
因為雌性不應該逃跑...
Because the females
should not escape...
我是說，雌性不應該逃跑。
I mean, the females
should not escape.
你不是說他們都是男性嗎。
I thought you said
they were all males.
我說的不是母猴子。
I'm not talking about
monkey females.
我說的是人類女性。
I'm talking about human females.
是的，因為他們想操一切會動的東西。
Yes, because they would like
to fuck everything that moves.
我覺得那不合我哥哥的口味。
I don't think that's
to my brother's taste.
聽我說完
Well, just hear me out.
有一個大結局。
There is a grande finale.
大自然的奇蹟。
An absolute wonder of nature.
幽靈巨獅。
The Gigantic Ghost Lion.
從頭到尾都是白色，
White from head to tail,
比維蘇威上空的雲層還要蒼白。
paler than the
clouds over Vesuvius.
這惡獸必從陰間上來，把他們都吞吃了。
This fierce beast will arise
from Hades, and devour them all.
你真是個變態，帕蘇斯。
You're a sick man, Passus.
嗯.好吧...
Hmm. Well...
而是一頭白色獅子。有趣.
But a white lion. Interesting.
我想親眼看看。
I wish to see it myself.
我得先逃出自己的牢籠。
I have to escape
my own cage first.
午夜在訓練場見。
Meet me at the Ludus
Beastius at midnight.
走了
Go.
Go now.
門
Door.
我要去小便。
I need to urinate.
圖密善
Domitian.
我希望你沒有承諾太多。它在哪裡？
I hope you didn't over
promise. Where is it?
就在這裡
Right over here.
你真漂亮。
How beautiful you are.
如此美麗，如此致命。
So very beautiful,
so very deadly.
我知道該怎麼利用你。
I know exactly how I'll use you.
你將是我的兄弟...
You'll be my brother...
提圖斯·弗拉維烏斯，羅馬的皇帝
Titus Flavius, Emperor of Rome,
耶路撒冷的征服者。
Conqueror of Jerusalem.
我想讓這隻野獸成為我們偉大的提圖斯·弗拉維亞努斯的象徵。
I want this beast to be a symbol
of our glorious Titus Flavianus.
- 當然了- 一隻嗜血成性的野獸。
- Of course.
- A beast with an unquenchable thirst for blood.
讓你的建築師重建一個耶路撒冷的複製品，適合馬戲團。
Have your builders reconstruct a
replica of Jerusalem, fit for the Circus.
我們要慶祝那座城市被攻陷！
We shall celebrate
the sacking of that city!
請允許我問一下
Allow me to ask.
白色獅子會攻擊誰？
Who will the white lion attack?
你一定要這麼遲鈍嗎？
Do you have to be so dim?
- 不。-你認為誰住在耶路撒冷？
- No.
- Who do you think lives in Jerusalem?
- 高盧人？- 啊啊
- Gauls?
- Uh-uh.
猶太人
Judeans.
一隻貓，即使是這麼兇猛的一隻，
A cat, even one
as fierce as this,
被人群的景象和聲音嚇到了
are terrified by the sight
and sounds of the crowd.
如果沒有訓練，它會凍結。
Without training,
it will freeze.
你想破壞圖密善的幻象嗎？
Would you like to
spoil Domitian's vision?
你想激起他的憤怒嗎？
Would you like to
excite his anger?
號
No.
曼尼留斯，
Manilius,
我的希臘男孩看到你在馬戲團賭博。
my Greek boy has seen
you betting at the Circus.
你以為脫下軍裝就能掩蓋你的所作所為嗎？
You think removing your military
garb is sufficient to hide what you do?
你的賭注，你的債務，
Your betting, your debts,
你從禁衛軍的薪津單上
your skimming from
the Praetorian payroll
讓你處於危險之中
to pay those debts
has put you at risk.
冒著生命危險，但不要害怕，
Mortal risk, but never fear,
我需要你的服務，
I have need of your service,
會有豐厚的獎勵
for which there will be
a substantial reward.
猶太人密謀殺害他們的王后，我哥哥的王后。
There's a plot amongst Judeans to
kill their queen, my brother's consort.
其中一個建築師，亞撒利雅，似乎是這個陰謀的領導者。
One of the architects, Azariah,
appears to be the leader of this plot.
我要你去逮捕幾個反叛的猶太人
I need you to arrest
some rebellious Judeans.
- 出去！出去！出去！- 這是什麼意思？
- Out! Out!
- What is the meaning of this?
- 你們都出去- 滾出去！
- All of you, out!
- Get out of here!
你為什麼要這麼做？
Why are you doing this?
你想幹什麼？
What do you want?
我們為什麼被捕？
Why are we arrested?
我被指控煽動叛亂並密謀殺害你們的女王。
I was told for sedition and
plotting to kill your Queen.
- 你說什麼？兩個都是謊言。
What? Lies, both of them.
我不在乎。
It doesn't matter to me.
明天你會死。你們所有人
Tomorrow you
will die. All of you.
被獅子殺死。
Killed by a lion.
這隻獅子很可能不會攻擊
This particular lion
will likely not attack
除非有人向野獸發起衝鋒。
unless somebody
charges the beast.
這就是你進來的地方。
That's where you come in.
我為什麼要拋棄我的生活
And why should I
throw my life away
為了方便你
for your convenience?
如果你這樣做，我會問帕蘇斯，遊戲大師，
If you do, I'll ask Passus,
the Master of Games,
放過你的女人和孩子
to spare your
women and children.
上帝保佑
By the Gods.
我討厭被關在這裡。
I hate being held
a prisoner here.
提圖斯皇帝萬歲
Hail Emperor Titus.
我真希望我能看到
I so wish I could see
羅馬人對猶太人的仇恨
the venom the Roman people
have for the Judeans, up close.
來了
Come.
她不是我們的女王！
She's not our queen!
可恥！
Shame!
已經是提圖斯盔甲上的裂縫了。
Already a chink
in Titus's armor.
回來
Come back.
我哥哥總是讓我吃驚。
My brother never
ceases to amaze me.
他怎麼能讓白麗萊茜坐在他旁邊？
How can he allow
Berenice to sit next to him?
他怎麼會沒想到呢？
How could he have
not seen this coming?
- 為了羅馬的榮耀. - 來了
- For the glory of Rome...
- Come.
為征服耶路撒冷而榮譽！
And to honor the
conquest of Jerusalem!
這是什麼？
What is this?
你說這次慶典是為了慶祝你登基。
You said this pageant was to
celebrate your accession to the throne.
隨著城市的燃燒，
As the city burns,
看看野蠻的猶太人，
behold the barbaric Judeans,
由他們的猶太女王貝麗萊茜領導
led by Berenice,
their Judean Queen.
現在，野蠻的猶太人
And now, the barbaric Judeans
將面對羅馬無與倫比的力量
will face the unparalleled
might of Rome.
他是非常強大的泰特斯·弗拉維亞努斯。
It is the very powerful
Titus Flavianus.
現在！
Now!
開門！
Open the gate!
看在上帝的份上，或者你的上帝，做點什麼吧！
For the sake of my God,
or your Gods, do something!
他們是我的人
These are my people.
做
Do it.
動手吧
Do it!
結束這一切
End this!
結束這一切！
End this now!
你認為他見過我嗎？
Do you think he's seen me?
是的
Yes.
He has.
這一次你做得太過分了
This time, you've gone too far.
在你殺了我之前聽我說完。
Hear me out before you kill me.
為這種厚顏無恥的行為編造理由？
Weave a justification
for such effrontery?
是的，你害怕聽到嗎？
Yes, are you too
afraid to hear it?
你得快點說。
You must speak quickly.
好好說話！
Speak well!
否則這把劍會刺穿你的心臟。
Or this sword will be struck
right through your heart.
我只是為你一石二鳥。
I merely killed two birds
with a single stone for you.
那些死在競技場的人密謀殺害你寶貴的女王並取代她。
Those who died in the arena were plotting to
kill your precious Queen and supplant her.
我救了她的命。
I saved her life.
讓暴民發泄他們對猶太人的仇恨。
And let the mob vent their
hatred for the Judeans.
你看，我從來沒聽說過這樣的陰謀。
You see, I've heard
nothing of such a plot.
這是你的缺點
That is your failing,
不是我的
not mine.
我可以提供證人，
I can provide witnesses,
- 和證據- 你看，證人，是可以收買的。
- and proof.
- See, witnesses, they can be bought.
和證據，它可以被製作。
And proof, it can be crafted.
如果你這麼想我，
Well, if you think that of me,
那就用劍
then use your sword.
如果需要的話，
If I needed to,
我會的
I would.
- 你幹嘛這麼刺激他？- 我知道
- Why do you provoke him so much?
- I know.
我應該離那該死的陽台遠點。
I should've stayed away
from that damn balcony.
但這場演出太精彩了，不容錯過。
But it was just too
good of a show to miss.
我責怪自己讓你說服我加入你的帝國平台。
I blame myself for allowing you to talk me
into joining you on the Imperial platform.
為什麼？去看我被撕成碎片的醜劇？
For what? To watch a hideous
travesty of myself being torn apart?
- 我不知道這是計劃好的。- 你是皇帝。
- I didn't know that was planned.
- You are Emperor.
你應該知道的。
You should have known.
皇帝金庫里的金子都花在你不同意的遊戲上了
The gold of the Emperor's coffers
spent on games you did not approve,
就在你眼皮底下
under your very nose.
我聽說那些被殺的人都在密謀反對你。
I've been told that those that
were killed were plotting against you.
誰告訴你的
Told by whom?
讓我猜猜你的毒蛇兄弟？
Let me guess.
Your viper brother?
他說他有證據。
He says that he has proof.
他說了很多話，但有多少是真的？
He says many things, but
how many of them are true?
我不能讓你走
I can't let you leave.
如果你把我拖回去，我就自殺。
If you have me dragged
back, I will take my own life.
不你...
No, you...
我求求你
I beg you.
請留下來
Please stay.
讓我來保護你
Let me protect you.
讓我證明給你看
Let me prove that to you.
但有一個條件
On one condition.
現在你讓我保護你。
Now you let me protect you.
他們永遠不會接受我做你的配偶。
They will never accept
me as your consort.
羅馬人討厭外國女王。
The Romans hate foreign queens.
他們必須學會接受你。
Then they will just have
to learn to accept you.
埃及豔后？
Cleopatra?
庫什的坎迪斯布狄卡？
Candace of Kush? Boudicca?
他們被接受了嗎？
Were they accepted?
和外國女王在一起只會削弱你在他們眼中的地位
To be with a foreign queen
only weakens you in their eyes.
為了堅強，
To be strong,
你必須反其道而行之
you must do the opposite.
你必須娶一個羅馬妻子
You must take a Roman wife
一個有錢有勢的高貴家族
of a good and august
family of wealth and power,
長久以來
of long standing.
把我放在陰影里。
Put me in the shadows.
這對你最好。
It is best for you.
你覺得什麼對你最好？
And what do you
think is best for you?
我是一個被征服的女王。我應該躲在陰影里。
I am a conquered queen.
My place is in the shadows.
你並不像你假裝的那樣無情。
You are not as
heartless as you pretend.
別那麼肯定
Don't be so sure.
孩子們都很尊敬你。
The children look up to you.
因為他們還是孩子。
That's because they're children.
他們崇拜任何人
They look up to anyone
他會給他們一些食物和硬幣。
who will give them a few scraps
of food and an occasional coin.
是的
I did.
你會說幾種語言？
How many languages do you speak?
不夠
Not enough.
你使用它們產生了很大的效果。
You use them to great effect.
真的嗎？真的？
Really?
你解除了人們的武裝。
You disarm people.
讓他們做你想做的事。
Get them to do what you want.
你就是這麼看的。
That's how you see it.
日安
Good day.
- 你欠我的-某種程度上
-Which you owe to
me -To some degree.
到那個程度，你會給我和我女兒更多的錢。
And to that degree, you will
pay me and my daughter more.
- 我會嗎？- 嗯嗯
- Will I?
- Mm-hmm.
奧拉的薪水漲了一半，我的漲了三倍。
Aura's salary up by
half, and mine tripled.
你做得太過火了。
You overreach.
好吧
Fine.
我們會把你那老鼠出沒的地方
We'll leave your
rat-infested insula
在另一家賭場找份工作
and find work at
another betting tavern.
我會把靈氣的增加四分之一你的增加一倍
I'll increase Aura's by a
quarter, and double yours.
像今天這樣繼續賺錢一個月，我們再談。
Keep bringing in the revenue like you did
today for a month, and we'll talk again.
太久了一周
That's too long. One week.
- 兩個. - 同意了
- Two.
- Agreed.
你在羅馬會過得很好的。
You'll do well in Rome.
我不是為這個來的。
I am not here for that.
要花更多的錢才能讓朱莉重獲自由
It will take a lot more
money to buy Jula's freedom.
而夸梅，一個角鬥士，可能是不可能的。
And Kwame, a gladiator,
probably impossible.
我會想辦法的
I will find a way.
求你了
Please.
請稍等
Please wait.
我有一個懇求。
I have an entreaty.
就像羅馬的其他人一樣。
As does every other
person in Rome.
我求你了我的孩子們被奪走了。
I beg of you. My children
have been taken from me.
我的...我兒子是競技場的角鬥士，
My... My son is a gladiator
at the Ludus Magnus,
還有我女兒
and my daughter,
她是個奴隸
she's a slave
在你父母的房子裡
in the house of your parents.
我聽說你有能力
I am told that you
have it in your power
釋放那些被判有罪的人和被囚禁的奴隸
to free those condemned
and those held as slaves.
不是我是
No, not me.
但我的護士長。
But my matron.
你能幫幫我嗎？
Could you help me?
但願我母親也為她的女兒流眼淚，就像你為你的女兒流眼淚一樣。
Would that my mother had had tears
for her daughter, as you do for yours.
我會和我的護士長說的
I will speak to my matron.
回到伊德斯，
Return on the Ides,
到時候我會給你答覆的。去吧
I will give you an
answer by then. Now, go.
昆圖斯
Quintus.
好久不見
It's been a while.
把手放在我能看到的地方。
Keep your hands
where I can see 'em.
不然我就把你的脊椎從根上切斷。
Or I'll sever your
spine at the root.
熊？
Ursus?
你留下燒死的那個男孩。
The boy you left to burn.
是我承擔了後果。
It was me who suffered
the consequences.
我以為你死了
I thought you were dead.
更糟！
Worse!
我被賣去當奴隸。無盡的地獄歲月。
I was sold as a galley
slave. Endless years in hell.
幸運的是，我應徵加入了羅馬軍隊
Luckily, I was drafted
into the Roman Army,
並為之奮鬥多年
and fought for them for years.
找到你很容易。
It was easy to find you.
在沒完沒了地說要去羅馬之後
After all the endless
talk about going to Rome
在著名的馬克西姆斯馬戲團工作
and work in the
famous Circus Maximus.
你知道奴隸殺死主人的懲罰
You know the punishment
for a slave killing his master
就是釘十字架
is crucifixion.
但對你來說太快了。
But that's too quick for you.
我要用你的尿淹死你！
I'm gonna drown
you in your own piss!
我不會殺你的
I'm not gonna kill you.
我要把你所有的錢都榨出來。
I'm gonna squeeze all
the money out of you.
我要奪走你的一切。
I'm gonna take
everything from you.
我不會讓你得逞的！
I'm not going to let
you get away with this!